This is Five Guys, the burger chain. One
of the interesting things about Five
Guys, very strange pricing. The burgers
are hugely expensive [music] because we
perceive actually expensive burgers as
being better. They are very, very good.
When you ask for fries, you have three
sizes to choose [music] from, small,
medium, or large. And they give you the
appropriate size of cup, they fill it to
the brim, and then they take another
scoop and chuck it into the bottom of
your brown paper bag. Why? The human
brain disproportionately values the
extra fries because they're [music] the
fries that you didn't have to give them.
You have to fill the cup up because if
you don't, you're shortch changing them.
It's a genuine mark of generosity
[music] because it's a something you
give someone that you're not legally
obliged to do. [music] And so what's
fascinating about that is if you gave
the job to a totally rational man, he'd
make the cups [music] larger. If you
gave the job to your finance director,
he'd tell you to stop giving away the
free fries cuz they're costing us $3.7
million a year in [music] potato costs.
Both of those people would destroy net
perceived